<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web 2 Ireland &#187; Web2.0 Summit</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/web20-summit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>EI&#8217;s Web2.0 Ireland Style</title>
		<link>/2008/11/eis-web20-ireland-style/</link>
		<comments>/2008/11/eis-web20-ireland-style/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 09:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web2.0 Summit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since I can&#8217;t find a web-page with this information on it anywhere, I thought it would be useful to publish a newsletter that EI in Palo Alto sent to a ton of people this week to coincide with the Web 2.0 Summit. It does a good job of highlighting some of the activity over here. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since I can&#8217;t find a web-page with this information on it anywhere, I thought it would be useful to publish a newsletter that EI in Palo Alto sent to a ton of people this week to coincide with the Web 2.0 Summit. It does a good job of highlighting some of the activity over here.</p>
<p>UPDATE: This info now on the <a href="http://enterprise-ireland.blogspot.com/2008/11/web-20-in-ireland.html">Enterprise Ireland Silicon Valley blog</a>. I&#8217;ll move them from Blogger to WordPress for free if they want <img src='/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p> </p>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><strong>Web 2.0 Ireland Style</strong>  </p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="550" valign="top">This week, the world´s web glitterati will converge on San Francisco for the <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?10zycjrl2DxehwQ6hDvZSw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Web 2.0 2008 Summit</a>. Al Gore, Lance Armstrong and other prominent speakers will join internet news makers to examine how the web, its technologies, values and culture, might be tapped to address the world&#8217;s most pressing limits and opportunities.  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>As a sponsor, <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?86JexhgLOXdJEMoa3S0pug5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Enterprise Ireland</a> will represent the entrepreneurs behind Ireland´s web 2.0 ingenuity and highlight their expanding stake in the global internet economy.</p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">   </p>
<p><strong>HERE´S JUST A SNAPSHOT OF IRELAND´S WEB 2.0 NEWSMAKERS</strong></p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?AcHXz7eywrUoWfNek7455Q5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">PollDaddy </a></span>was snapped up by Automattic (company behind WordPress) last month. PollDaddy provides polling and survey widgets for blogs, websites and social networks.</span></p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?sA8QK3YB/W4U4sE2xyYqEw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Contrast</a> </span>just launched <span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?XLvyFJyb06Q9o4Qo8fFOjw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Qwitter</a> </span>an application that alerts Twitter users when contacts &#8220;un-follow&#8221; them. With 16,000+ sign-ups in less than 2 weeks, the service is adding a new dynamic to Twitter-based relationships. </p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?1ioKOIqRq4RgBsoUZKd6eQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">dotMobi </a></span>launched Version 2.0 of DeviceAtlas, the world´s most popular mobile device database. dotMobi is the company behind the .mobi internet domain designed to help consumers find mobile-friendly content.</p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?YA5PSTLMeBrg+cCYTYjPoA5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Muzu TV </a></span>signed agreements with Sony BMG, Ministry Of Sound, Skint Loaded (Fat Boy Slim&#8217;s label), Defected, and hundreds of other indies. Muzu TV is a new music TV website and distribution platform that enables bands and record labels to broadcast their music video on the web and get paid wherever it goes through a share in ad revenue. </p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?DXtqzoUV9aqx41sLAhu+bw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Nooked </a></span>delivers shopping deals direct to consumers&#8217; desktop, Myspace, Facebook, blog, start page, and mobile phones through widget-based technology.</p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?fXa9i2ZXeGfUyl4P76y+4g5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Dial2Do </a></span>is a phone-service for drivers. It lets you get things done safely and conveniently by just using your voice. You can send text messages, send and listen to email, create reminders, update your Twitter stream and use a range of other services by just calling a number and saying what you want to do. A winner at the Silicon Valley Association of Startup Entrepreneurs Launch:2008 event, Dial2Do was voted as the company most likely to succeed in the Media and Mobility category. </p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?LdDS9mNbmcyBPlkNeXKGbg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">LouderVoice </a></span>just made it easier for businesses to turn customer feedback and reviews into revenue-generating word-of-mouth campaigns. The company´s &#8220;white label&#8221; reviews system can be added to any website, providing a quick and easy way for visitors to review and comment.</p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?35nPBym51E2BEjLz9mxbcw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">PutPlace </a></span></span><span>gathers all your valuable digital stuff [photos, documents, email, music, videos] from all your PCs and laptops. It backs up everything, securely stores it, and organizes it all so you can find or share your files from anywhere. Service features include: Simple, reliable automatic online backup that runs in the background; easy back up of files from multiple computers to the same account; secure access to your files from anywhere; automatically allows you to share the files you choose on services like Flickr; versions all stored files, ensuring that you never lose an old version of a file. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?sJtqikwnvC7myBmpE4rXLQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Finetuna</a> </span></span><span>makes it easy to share notes on images, photos and other graphics files. Since its launch just 4 months ago, Finetuna has already surpassed the 50,000 user mark. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?OKjtK5LZwK8kn1e5ospYKQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Abaltat&#8217;s</a></span></span><span> music creation tools make it possible for anyone to be a composer &#8211; creating original, perfectly synched, royalty-free music to match their video. A must for the growing number of creators of video-based content, from TV and film to online video advertising. Behind Abaltat is a group of experienced TV producers, editors, musicologists and the most imaginative programmers in Ireland. The result: a unique software product that has earned the company a spot on the shortlist of the Irish Software Association&#8217;s Technical Innovation Award and New Company of the Year Award. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?b3S1DqlAx3l1hijBlwqLhg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">RevaHealth</a></span></span><span> is cutting healthcare costs for budget-conscious consumers by connecting them with dentists and cosmetic clinics in countries where they can realize savings of more than 50%. Every week, more than 1000 people take advantage of RevaHealth´s comprehensive search services. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?2Etaua5wnqm7ghSsJorCNQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Toddle</a></span></span><span> makes it easy to create pretty HTML newsletters, using an interactive, easy-to-use web app. The product emerged from Beta to rave reviews and is seeing fast adoption by customers in Ireland and the US.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?4A1ZdVdoBS7mdqNwMe8Epw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">IGOpeople</a></span></span><span> is gearing up to launch its beta service in December. The company provides a network for individuals and small businesses to easily communicate and share information. The service is drawing interest especially from business owners who can now reach highly targeted audiences more efficiently than through traditional advertising and telephone support. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?hyflC8gpiyRCdSDJZeKX/w5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Hosting365</a></span></span><span> is a managed services and data centre facility provider and Ireland´s only commercial cloud computing provider. Ranked as one of Ireland&#8217;s fastest growing technology companies for the past 2 years, the company recently reported sales for its cloud computing services of €2.5 million for the first six months of the year.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?ISbjXBm9AFtJp0IJNTkq7A5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Sxoop Technologie</a></span></span><span> is an imaging software company which specializes in web-based photo solutions.  They recently picked up the &#8216;Most Innovative Website&#8217; award at the inaugural Irish Web Awards for their web-based photo-editing website <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?jSd1DqHJdMeaMsHLzhOaqg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">http://pixenate.com/</a>. Sxoop Technologies licenses their photo-software to social networking and photo-merchandising services. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?gGdW+31R0xN0E/I6njKtVg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Web Reservations International (WRI)</a></span></span><span> is a leading provider of online lodging reservations through its own network of highly trafficked sites (Hostelworld.com, <a href="http://boo.com/" target="_blank">boo.com</a>, Trav.com and Hostels.com) along with 3,000+ affiliate partners. Through its flagship Hostelworld.com, WRI has become the leading online reservations provider to the budget travel sector, while <a href="http://boo.com/" target="_blank">boo.com</a> combines travel search, reviews and social networking in a web 2.0 platform.</span></p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><strong>IRELAND: DRAWING THE BEST AND THE BRIGHTEST</strong>  </p>
<p><span>With a reputation for nurturing internet entrepreneurs, Ireland has long drawn companies like Yahoo, Google and many others who selected the country as a location for their international presence. Last month, Facebook followed suit by establishing its international HQ in Dublin. <br />
Read more <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?uU9dCUviSQdJID5GgQ4Isw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">here</a> </span></p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">   </p>
<p><strong>WEB 2.0 WHAT´S NEXT?</strong></p>
<p><span>To answer that million-dollar question, EI will join forces with the <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?iUpS/LUp5mfpsHqflho55w5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">San Francisco Irish Network</a> to host executives from Facebook, Google, Yahoo, Cuil and Skydeck for a spirited panel discussion that coincides with the web 2.0 Summit. <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?3sL7ZTYlrhvvW0n+w8M44g5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Tom Foremski</a> of<a href="http://siliconvalleywatcher.com/" target="_blank">siliconvalleywatcher.com</a> will moderate. Event details are <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?oouR1/xVTXjU4aqDfNAM0g5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">here</a> </span></p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><strong><br />
</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3" height="20"> </td>
</tr>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2008/11/eis-web20-ireland-style/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
