<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web 2 Ireland &#187; ei</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ei/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Ireland to Exhibit at Le Web 2010!</title>
		<link>/2010/10/ireland-to-exhibit-at-le-web-2010/</link>
		<comments>/2010/10/ireland-to-exhibit-at-le-web-2010/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 11:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[france]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[le web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leweb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leweb10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leweb2010]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paris]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1864</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been finding it hard to keep this news under my hat since the idea was first floated a few months back. There will be an Ireland Pavilion at Le Web in Paris this year! This is just an absolutely brilliant idea and huge kudos goes to all of those in Enterprise Ireland who conceived [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been finding it hard to keep this news under my hat since the idea was first floated a few months back. There will be an Ireland Pavilion at <a href="http://www.leweb.net/">Le Web</a> in Paris this year! This is just an absolutely brilliant idea and huge kudos goes to all of those in <a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/en/">Enterprise Ireland</a> who conceived the idea and then got full support for it both internally and from the IDA.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.leweb.net/"><img class="size-full wp-image-1873  aligncenter" title="Le Web" src="//web2ireland.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/leweb_logo.png" alt="" width="100" height="100" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.leweb.net/"></a><a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/en/"><img class="size-full wp-image-1874  aligncenter" title="Enterprise Ireland" src="//web2ireland.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/Logo_NoStrapLine.jpg" alt="" width="270" height="78" /></a></p>
<p>Le Web is the most important conference about the web in Europe every year. You will not see a more impressive collection of heavy hitters in one place anywhere else. It&#8217;s the kind of place where you can meet people like Marissa Meyer or Niklas Zennström or Fred Wilson. My trivial claim to fame is that I think I&#8217;m the only Irish person to attend every year since 2006 and I&#8217;ve watched it getting better and better.</p>
<p>This year some of the speakers on December 8th and 9th include Dennis Crowley, JP Rangaswami, Toni Schneider and Carlos Ghosn.</p>
<p>The importance of Ireland having its own stand at Le Web cannot be underestimated. The first country ever to have a pavilion like this at the show. One place where global businesses, VCs, other European/US start-ups and leading tech bloggers can see the best of Irish web start-ups. One place where you can point people to in the coming weeks and say &#8220;we&#8217;ll be there, pop on over for a coffee&#8221;.</p>
<p>A problem with giant events like Le Web is that co-ordinating meetings can be a nightmare. People are being pulled in every direction and we are all vying for our own little bit of attention. This stand solves that problem in one fell swoop.</p>
<p>I am convinced this genius move will get a ton of coverage from all the attending press. Who wouldn&#8217;t be intrigued by this?  After all the relentless bad news about Ireland in the global press where we allowed a cabal of innumerate imbeciles to rape our country, this gives journos a totally new, positive growth story to tell. &#8220;Ireland may be screwed now but these start-ups are re-building it from the ground up&#8221;.</p>
<p>So, interested?</p>
<p>The EI package is as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>A full LE WEB pass, giving you access to all the seminars, networking events and competitions over the two days</li>
<li>Use of a dedicated 18m² meeting place/demo area which your company can use to meet with key contacts and demo your solution.</li>
<li>A drinks reception on the Irish pavilion on the evening of 8th December for EI clients and your guests.</li>
<li>In the run up to LE WEB, EI overseas offices will endeavour to link your company in with influential people from overseas markets that will be coming to LE WEB.</li>
<li>Your company’s profile and contact details in Enterprise Ireland’s Internet marketing materials designed specifically for the event</li>
</ul>
<p>EI is providing this at a totally knock-down price.</p>
<p>There is really only one limitation which is that you must be an EI client to apply to be on the stand. There are only 14 slots so not everyone is going to get through. To apply, simply contact Karen Hallez in the EI Paris office at Karen.Hallez@enterprise-ireland.com and she will send you an application form and details on the cost etc. <strong>They really need to get this wrapped up in the next few days so apply now.</strong></p>
<p>Also don&#8217;t forget that this is the last weekend where you can enter the <a href="http://leweb.producteev.com/home.php">Le Web Startup Competition</a>.</p>
<p>I know I&#8217;ve been lauding Enterprise Ireland a lot recently, but with good reason. Of all the state and semi-state bodies I&#8217;ve dealt with since the country went to hell, EI and all its staff are the ones that more than rose to the challenge and they are impressing me with every single encounter. Right now, the way EI operates shows the best of what the public sector and private sector working together should be about.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2010/10/ireland-to-exhibit-at-le-web-2010/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>iGAP &#8211; Internet Growth Accelerator Programme Launches</title>
		<link>/2009/09/igap-internet-growth-accelerator-programme-launches/</link>
		<comments>/2009/09/igap-internet-growth-accelerator-programme-launches/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 15:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[igap]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1430</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today saw the launch of a new joint initiative between Enterprise Ireland and the Internet Growth Alliance headed by Colm Lyon of Realex called iGAP. Over 6 months from November 2009 onwards, iGAP will focus on practical learning and intensive support for Irish web businesses who wish to grow aggressively at an international level. The [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today saw the launch of a new joint initiative between Enterprise Ireland and the <a href="http://www.alliance.ie/">Internet Growth Alliance</a> headed by Colm Lyon of Realex called <a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/igap/">iGAP</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/igap/"><img alt="" src="//www.enterprise-ireland.com/NR/rdonlyres/B01E5B38-5507-4FD8-A62B-5061689ADECA/0/iGAPtopbanner.JPG" title="iGAP" class="aligncenter" width="556" height="62" /></a></p>
<p>Over 6 months from November 2009 onwards, iGAP will focus on practical learning and intensive support for Irish web businesses who wish to grow aggressively at an international level. </p>
<p>The programme will culminate in a funding pitch scenario where the participants be put to the test by experienced venture capital and angel investors. Participants will also be partnered with an experienced business leader who will act as an implementation coach to ensure the programme learning is embedded into the company.</p>
<p>The full cost of the Internet Growth Acceleration Programme is €10k per company (2 participants). Enterprise Ireland will fund 80% of this cost leaving a company fee of €2k.</p>
<p>A very welcome aspect of the programme is that it is open to to non-clients of Enterprise Ireland too so it won&#8217;t be a love-in of the usual suspects. The presence of some real heavy hitters in the industry means this really is a very serious initiative and has tons of upside for those who participate.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/igap/How+to+Participate.htm">Closing Date</a> for Applications is October 16th.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2009/09/igap-internet-growth-accelerator-programme-launches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starting a Tech Business?</title>
		<link>/2009/03/starting-a-tech-business/</link>
		<comments>/2009/03/starting-a-tech-business/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 12:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1085</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Enterprise Ireland is doing an information evening on starting a tech business in Letterkenny on 25th March. It looks like a very useful session with speakers on: Business Planning Process EI supports to High Potential Start ups Paul McNulty on starting his own Technology Business If you wish to attend, please contact marian.roberts@enterprise-ireland.com]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Enterprise Ireland is doing an information evening on starting a tech business in Letterkenny on 25th March.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" title="EI" src="//www.enterprise-ireland.com/eicms/images/corpimages/logo.gif" alt="" width="94" height="112" /></p>
<p>It looks like a very useful session with speakers on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Business Planning Process</li>
<li>EI supports to High Potential Start ups</li>
<li>Paul McNulty on starting his own Technology Business</li>
</ul>
<p>If you wish to attend, please contact marian.roberts@enterprise-ireland.com</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2009/03/starting-a-tech-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should Government get involved with VCs ?</title>
		<link>/2008/12/should-government-get-involved-with-vcs/</link>
		<comments>/2008/12/should-government-get-involved-with-vcs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 17:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VCfunds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web2ireland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=939</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Techcrunch France editor &#8211; and LGiLab VC in Israel &#8211; Ouriel Ohayon has a great piece on Can governments become good VCs? This topic came up in VC discussion at last week&#8217;s LeWeb &#8211; and Ireland was mentioned as an example. Enterprise Ireland in a June press release provided an update on the 2007-2012 Seed [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://fr.techcrunch.com/">Techcrunch France editor</a> &#8211; and <a href="http://lgilab.typepad.com/">LGiLab VC in Israel</a> &#8211; Ouriel Ohayon has a great piece on <a href="http://ouriel.typepad.com/myblog/2008/12/can-governments.html">Can governments become good VCs?</a></p>
<p>This topic came up in <a href="http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/933026">VC discussion</a> at last week&#8217;s <a href="http://www.lewebparis.com/">LeWeb</a> &#8211; and Ireland was mentioned as an example.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/">Enterprise Ireland</a> in a <a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/News/Press+Releases/2008/PressJun032008.htm">June press release</a> provided an update on the <a href="http://www.entemp.ie/press/2007/20070722.htm">2007-2012 Seed and Venture Capital (VC) Programme</a></p>
<p>To date €148.75m has been committed to 8 Seed &#038; Venture Funds. </p>
<p>Of these, 6 have completed first closings, including </p>
<p>- Delta Partners [100m fund]<br />
- AIB Seed Capital Fund [30m fund]<br />
- Atlantic Bridge Ventures<br />
- Kernel Capital Partners [70m fund]<br />
- Fountain Healthcare Partners &#8211; not for technology &#8211; life science fund.<br />
- NCB Ventures &#8211; [75m fund] &#8211; closed its fund in November.</p>
<p>€275m funds readily available &#8211; and from EI press release &#8211; 8 funds [2 funds still to close] have succeeded in raising in excess of €500m for investment in early stage and growing companies.</p>
<p>Enterprise Ireland announced that €30m is remaining and is now available for co-investment &#8211; and a recent advertisement in the <a href="http://www.ft.com/">FT</a> is targetting UK VCs for partnership.</p>
<p>Given the recent <a href="http://www.nesta.org.uk/attacking-the-recession/">UK news @ Government funds for NESTA</a>, the UK’s National Endowment for Science, Technology and the Arts, will oversee a £1bn emergency venture capital fund aimed at pre-revenue technology start-up firms &#8211; and the <a href="http://uk.techcrunch.com/2008/12/08/is-this-1bn-from-nesta-new-money-will-private-equity-really-join-in-and-why-is-nesta-not-answering-their-email/">follow on discussion</a> &#8211; We&#8217;d like to hear from Web2Ireland companies who have raised monies from these EI backed funds [make sure you update your Crunchbase details]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2008/12/should-government-get-involved-with-vcs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>EI&#8217;s Web2.0 Ireland Style</title>
		<link>/2008/11/eis-web20-ireland-style/</link>
		<comments>/2008/11/eis-web20-ireland-style/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 09:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web2.0 Summit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since I can&#8217;t find a web-page with this information on it anywhere, I thought it would be useful to publish a newsletter that EI in Palo Alto sent to a ton of people this week to coincide with the Web 2.0 Summit. It does a good job of highlighting some of the activity over here. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since I can&#8217;t find a web-page with this information on it anywhere, I thought it would be useful to publish a newsletter that EI in Palo Alto sent to a ton of people this week to coincide with the Web 2.0 Summit. It does a good job of highlighting some of the activity over here.</p>
<p>UPDATE: This info now on the <a href="http://enterprise-ireland.blogspot.com/2008/11/web-20-in-ireland.html">Enterprise Ireland Silicon Valley blog</a>. I&#8217;ll move them from Blogger to WordPress for free if they want <img src='/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p> </p>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><strong>Web 2.0 Ireland Style</strong>  </p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="550" valign="top">This week, the world´s web glitterati will converge on San Francisco for the <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?10zycjrl2DxehwQ6hDvZSw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Web 2.0 2008 Summit</a>. Al Gore, Lance Armstrong and other prominent speakers will join internet news makers to examine how the web, its technologies, values and culture, might be tapped to address the world&#8217;s most pressing limits and opportunities.  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>As a sponsor, <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?86JexhgLOXdJEMoa3S0pug5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Enterprise Ireland</a> will represent the entrepreneurs behind Ireland´s web 2.0 ingenuity and highlight their expanding stake in the global internet economy.</p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">   </p>
<p><strong>HERE´S JUST A SNAPSHOT OF IRELAND´S WEB 2.0 NEWSMAKERS</strong></p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?AcHXz7eywrUoWfNek7455Q5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">PollDaddy </a></span>was snapped up by Automattic (company behind WordPress) last month. PollDaddy provides polling and survey widgets for blogs, websites and social networks.</span></p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?sA8QK3YB/W4U4sE2xyYqEw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Contrast</a> </span>just launched <span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?XLvyFJyb06Q9o4Qo8fFOjw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Qwitter</a> </span>an application that alerts Twitter users when contacts &#8220;un-follow&#8221; them. With 16,000+ sign-ups in less than 2 weeks, the service is adding a new dynamic to Twitter-based relationships. </p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?1ioKOIqRq4RgBsoUZKd6eQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">dotMobi </a></span>launched Version 2.0 of DeviceAtlas, the world´s most popular mobile device database. dotMobi is the company behind the .mobi internet domain designed to help consumers find mobile-friendly content.</p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?YA5PSTLMeBrg+cCYTYjPoA5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Muzu TV </a></span>signed agreements with Sony BMG, Ministry Of Sound, Skint Loaded (Fat Boy Slim&#8217;s label), Defected, and hundreds of other indies. Muzu TV is a new music TV website and distribution platform that enables bands and record labels to broadcast their music video on the web and get paid wherever it goes through a share in ad revenue. </p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?DXtqzoUV9aqx41sLAhu+bw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Nooked </a></span>delivers shopping deals direct to consumers&#8217; desktop, Myspace, Facebook, blog, start page, and mobile phones through widget-based technology.</p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?fXa9i2ZXeGfUyl4P76y+4g5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Dial2Do </a></span>is a phone-service for drivers. It lets you get things done safely and conveniently by just using your voice. You can send text messages, send and listen to email, create reminders, update your Twitter stream and use a range of other services by just calling a number and saying what you want to do. A winner at the Silicon Valley Association of Startup Entrepreneurs Launch:2008 event, Dial2Do was voted as the company most likely to succeed in the Media and Mobility category. </p>
<p><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?LdDS9mNbmcyBPlkNeXKGbg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">LouderVoice </a></span>just made it easier for businesses to turn customer feedback and reviews into revenue-generating word-of-mouth campaigns. The company´s &#8220;white label&#8221; reviews system can be added to any website, providing a quick and easy way for visitors to review and comment.</p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?35nPBym51E2BEjLz9mxbcw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">PutPlace </a></span></span><span>gathers all your valuable digital stuff [photos, documents, email, music, videos] from all your PCs and laptops. It backs up everything, securely stores it, and organizes it all so you can find or share your files from anywhere. Service features include: Simple, reliable automatic online backup that runs in the background; easy back up of files from multiple computers to the same account; secure access to your files from anywhere; automatically allows you to share the files you choose on services like Flickr; versions all stored files, ensuring that you never lose an old version of a file. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?sJtqikwnvC7myBmpE4rXLQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Finetuna</a> </span></span><span>makes it easy to share notes on images, photos and other graphics files. Since its launch just 4 months ago, Finetuna has already surpassed the 50,000 user mark. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?OKjtK5LZwK8kn1e5ospYKQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Abaltat&#8217;s</a></span></span><span> music creation tools make it possible for anyone to be a composer &#8211; creating original, perfectly synched, royalty-free music to match their video. A must for the growing number of creators of video-based content, from TV and film to online video advertising. Behind Abaltat is a group of experienced TV producers, editors, musicologists and the most imaginative programmers in Ireland. The result: a unique software product that has earned the company a spot on the shortlist of the Irish Software Association&#8217;s Technical Innovation Award and New Company of the Year Award. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?b3S1DqlAx3l1hijBlwqLhg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">RevaHealth</a></span></span><span> is cutting healthcare costs for budget-conscious consumers by connecting them with dentists and cosmetic clinics in countries where they can realize savings of more than 50%. Every week, more than 1000 people take advantage of RevaHealth´s comprehensive search services. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?2Etaua5wnqm7ghSsJorCNQ5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Toddle</a></span></span><span> makes it easy to create pretty HTML newsletters, using an interactive, easy-to-use web app. The product emerged from Beta to rave reviews and is seeing fast adoption by customers in Ireland and the US.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?4A1ZdVdoBS7mdqNwMe8Epw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">IGOpeople</a></span></span><span> is gearing up to launch its beta service in December. The company provides a network for individuals and small businesses to easily communicate and share information. The service is drawing interest especially from business owners who can now reach highly targeted audiences more efficiently than through traditional advertising and telephone support. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?hyflC8gpiyRCdSDJZeKX/w5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Hosting365</a></span></span><span> is a managed services and data centre facility provider and Ireland´s only commercial cloud computing provider. Ranked as one of Ireland&#8217;s fastest growing technology companies for the past 2 years, the company recently reported sales for its cloud computing services of €2.5 million for the first six months of the year.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?ISbjXBm9AFtJp0IJNTkq7A5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Sxoop Technologie</a></span></span><span> is an imaging software company which specializes in web-based photo solutions.  They recently picked up the &#8216;Most Innovative Website&#8217; award at the inaugural Irish Web Awards for their web-based photo-editing website <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?jSd1DqHJdMeaMsHLzhOaqg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">http://pixenate.com/</a>. Sxoop Technologies licenses their photo-software to social networking and photo-merchandising services. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><span><a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?gGdW+31R0xN0E/I6njKtVg5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Web Reservations International (WRI)</a></span></span><span> is a leading provider of online lodging reservations through its own network of highly trafficked sites (Hostelworld.com, <a href="http://boo.com/" target="_blank">boo.com</a>, Trav.com and Hostels.com) along with 3,000+ affiliate partners. Through its flagship Hostelworld.com, WRI has become the leading online reservations provider to the budget travel sector, while <a href="http://boo.com/" target="_blank">boo.com</a> combines travel search, reviews and social networking in a web 2.0 platform.</span></p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><strong>IRELAND: DRAWING THE BEST AND THE BRIGHTEST</strong>  </p>
<p><span>With a reputation for nurturing internet entrepreneurs, Ireland has long drawn companies like Yahoo, Google and many others who selected the country as a location for their international presence. Last month, Facebook followed suit by establishing its international HQ in Dublin. <br />
Read more <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?uU9dCUviSQdJID5GgQ4Isw5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">here</a> </span></p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">   </p>
<p><strong>WEB 2.0 WHAT´S NEXT?</strong></p>
<p><span>To answer that million-dollar question, EI will join forces with the <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?iUpS/LUp5mfpsHqflho55w5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">San Francisco Irish Network</a> to host executives from Facebook, Google, Yahoo, Cuil and Skydeck for a spirited panel discussion that coincides with the web 2.0 Summit. <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?3sL7ZTYlrhvvW0n+w8M44g5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">Tom Foremski</a> of<a href="http://siliconvalleywatcher.com/" target="_blank">siliconvalleywatcher.com</a> will moderate. Event details are <a href="http://enews.customerminds.com/c.asp?oouR1/xVTXjU4aqDfNAM0g5GOi3SAtRUWTQma8rRM6wg" target="_blank">here</a> </span></p>
<p> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><img src="//media.customerminds.com/Files/517/images/EI-dotted-line.png" alt="" width="555" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3"><strong><br />
</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3" height="20"> </td>
</tr>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2008/11/eis-web20-ireland-style/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Irish man on stage for Apple Developer Conference</title>
		<link>/2008/06/irish-man-on-stage-for-apple-developer-conference/</link>
		<comments>/2008/06/irish-man-on-stage-for-apple-developer-conference/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 21:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benmosse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web2ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wwdc]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=624</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Loads of excitement at the Apple Developer Conference &#8211; with an Irish man centre stage &#8211; and a good friend of Web2Ireland Ben Mosse &#8211; formely of Enterprise Ireland &#8211; and now VP, Associated Press &#8211; announced a cool iPhone application that his team developed out of New York. Do check the video&#8217;s out from [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/06/09/the-games-begin-live-coverage-of-apple-wwwc-event-in-san-francisco/">Loads of excitement</a> at the <a href="http://developer.apple.com/wwdc/">Apple Developer Conference</a> &#8211; with an Irish man centre stage &#8211; and a good friend of Web2Ireland</p>
<p><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/mosse">Ben Mosse</a> &#8211; formely of Enterprise Ireland &#8211; and now VP, <a href="http://www.apnews.com/">Associated Press</a> &#8211; announced a <a href="http://www.apnews.com/">cool iPhone application</a> that his team developed out of New York.</p>
<p>Do check the video&#8217;s out from the Steve Jobs keynote &#8211; available in iTunes</p>
<p>Question &#8211; any Irish startups working on iPhone platform &#8211; see <a href="http://gigaom.com/2008/06/11/venture-capitalists-eyeing-iphone-start-ups/">related note from Om</a> &#8211; do drop us a note in the comments</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2008/06/irish-man-on-stage-for-apple-developer-conference/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
