<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
		>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Virtual and Realworld Art rubs shoulders at Ten Cubed</title>
	<atom:link href="/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 15:37:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: The Grid Live &#187; Second Life News for February 9, 2008</title>
		<link>/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-563</link>
		<dc:creator>The Grid Live &#187; Second Life News for February 9, 2008</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2008 08:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/2008/02/01/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-563</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[...] Web 2.0 Ireland Virtual and Realworld Art rubs shoulders at Ten Cubed Quote from the site - Haydn Shaughnessy has just launched the virtual art gallery Ten Cubed in [...]]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[...] Web 2.0 Ireland Virtual and Realworld Art rubs shoulders at Ten Cubed Quote from the site &#8211; Haydn Shaughnessy has just launched the virtual art gallery Ten Cubed in [...]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Conor O'Neill</title>
		<link>/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-562</link>
		<dc:creator>Conor O'Neill</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 11:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/2008/02/01/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-562</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Are they serious? But you can&#039;t even get a sense of the scale of a piece on a web-site, let alone get a feeling for how it looks in-context.

I think my daughter prefers just creating Miis than playing the games. Wii controller shows what is possible with off the shelf technology and some smart thinking (ditto the DS). Sony has a lot to learn from Nintendo.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are they serious? But you can&#8217;t even get a sense of the scale of a piece on a web-site, let alone get a feeling for how it looks in-context.</p>
<p>I think my daughter prefers just creating Miis than playing the games. Wii controller shows what is possible with off the shelf technology and some smart thinking (ditto the DS). Sony has a lot to learn from Nintendo.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: haydn</title>
		<link>/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-561</link>
		<dc:creator>haydn</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 10:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/2008/02/01/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes, awesome.

I&#039;ve been having some of this debate also over at the guardian blogs - their arts reviewer picked up the launch - people there are saying art is best viewed on a website rather than in a 3D world. I can hardly believe it.
http://blogs.guardian.co.uk/art/2008/01/ catch_of_the_day_second_lifes.html

I&#039;m struggling to work out how they could be right . On the wii my kids each have about 20 avatars each - they have a new hobby - making avatars. We have to hydrate them after half an hour of playing they are so into the movement.

I can&#039;t imagine this isn&#039;t going to be the UI very soon on the web - all that wil stop it is Linden Labs incompetence at dealing with the development of their platform.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, awesome.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been having some of this debate also over at the guardian blogs &#8211; their arts reviewer picked up the launch &#8211; people there are saying art is best viewed on a website rather than in a 3D world. I can hardly believe it.<br />
<a href="http://blogs.guardian.co.uk/art/2008/01/" rel="nofollow">http://blogs.guardian.co.uk/art/2008/01/</a> catch_of_the_day_second_lifes.html</p>
<p>I&#8217;m struggling to work out how they could be right . On the wii my kids each have about 20 avatars each &#8211; they have a new hobby &#8211; making avatars. We have to hydrate them after half an hour of playing they are so into the movement.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t imagine this isn&#8217;t going to be the UI very soon on the web &#8211; all that wil stop it is Linden Labs incompetence at dealing with the development of their platform.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Conor O'Neill</title>
		<link>/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-560</link>
		<dc:creator>Conor O'Neill</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/2008/02/01/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.redmonk.com/jgovernor/2007/10/16/the-gaping-void-gets-his-wii-hands-on/]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.redmonk.com/jgovernor/2007/10/16/the-gaping-void-gets-his-wii-hands-on/" rel="nofollow">http://www.redmonk.com/jgovernor/2007/10/16/the-gaping-void-gets-his-wii-hands-on/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Conor O'Neill</title>
		<link>/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-559</link>
		<dc:creator>Conor O'Neill</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/2008/02/01/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-559</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh you really grabbed me with the Wii mention there! Dennis Howlett recently linked to an awesome video demo by some SAP people of using the controllers with business visualisation software. I&#039;ll see if I can dig it out. We&#039;re only scratching the surface of what can be done with UIs.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh you really grabbed me with the Wii mention there! Dennis Howlett recently linked to an awesome video demo by some SAP people of using the controllers with business visualisation software. I&#8217;ll see if I can dig it out. We&#8217;re only scratching the surface of what can be done with UIs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: haydn</title>
		<link>/2008/02/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-558</link>
		<dc:creator>haydn</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 11:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/2008/02/01/virtual-and-realworld-art-rubs-shoulders-at-ten-cubed/#comment-558</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks for those kind words - I too am  a Second Life sceptic but recently I got talking with Robert Lai who runs the Chinese Cyber Recreation District. 

Robert&#039;s job is to get 150 million Chinese families and businesses into virtual worlds by October 2010. In Korea over 70% of the population are already in virtual worlds. Purely from the point of view of where commerce is headed, as we increasingly need to save on travel and other carbon output activities, virtual worlds make sense.

But they are also far better interfaces than the keyboard is. True right now we manipulate avatars through keyboards but that&#039;s fast disappearing - a voice presence is normal and natural and we&#039;ll no doubt go to joysticks and then pure movement, as with the Wii. People who type into the computer to reach me on the web will be redundant in five years time.

We&#039;re also engaged more and more in an economy based around creativity and imagination. In a virtual world you can understand that better.

One of the things Ten Cubed is doing is to sell totally intangible assets - simulations. We have art work in signed and numbered editions that we believe will become part of a new series of market for intangibles - they exist in virtuality and to a certain extent in the imagination. I think these will be products of the future and I can well imagine going to auctions in three years time to bid on works of value that have no physical reality.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks for those kind words &#8211; I too am  a Second Life sceptic but recently I got talking with Robert Lai who runs the Chinese Cyber Recreation District. </p>
<p>Robert&#8217;s job is to get 150 million Chinese families and businesses into virtual worlds by October 2010. In Korea over 70% of the population are already in virtual worlds. Purely from the point of view of where commerce is headed, as we increasingly need to save on travel and other carbon output activities, virtual worlds make sense.</p>
<p>But they are also far better interfaces than the keyboard is. True right now we manipulate avatars through keyboards but that&#8217;s fast disappearing &#8211; a voice presence is normal and natural and we&#8217;ll no doubt go to joysticks and then pure movement, as with the Wii. People who type into the computer to reach me on the web will be redundant in five years time.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re also engaged more and more in an economy based around creativity and imagination. In a virtual world you can understand that better.</p>
<p>One of the things Ten Cubed is doing is to sell totally intangible assets &#8211; simulations. We have art work in signed and numbered editions that we believe will become part of a new series of market for intangibles &#8211; they exist in virtuality and to a certain extent in the imagination. I think these will be products of the future and I can well imagine going to auctions in three years time to bid on works of value that have no physical reality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
