<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web 2 Ireland &#187; sqt training</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/sqt-training/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Irish iPhone App School Announced</title>
		<link>/2009/06/irish-iphone-app-school-announced/</link>
		<comments>/2009/06/irish-iphone-app-school-announced/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 08:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[damien mulley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patrick collison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sqt training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is the sort of news I love reporting. We now have an App School in Ireland. Over the course of 5 days you can learn how to build iPhone Apps. Run by SQT Training, Patrick Collison and Damien Mulley, this will give you all the skills you get to get your App built and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the sort of news I love reporting. We now have an <a href="http://appschool.ie/">App School</a> in Ireland. Over the course of 5 days you can learn how to build iPhone Apps. Run by SQT Training, Patrick Collison and <a href="http://mulley.ie/">Damien Mulley</a>, this will give you all the skills you get to get your App built and launched. At only €1500 for the week, that&#8217;s a bargain considering how much traditional programming training courses cost. The first course is on in the Castleknock Hotel Dublin from July 20-24.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" title="iPhone" src="//images.apple.com/iphone/home/images/hero-1-20090608.jpg" alt="" width="412" height="167" /></p>
<p>One of the best courses I ever did was back in 2006 when Ryan Carson presented his one day workshop, &#8220;A-Z: How to Build a Web App&#8221;. Because it wasn&#8217;t just about tech but also about all the pitfalls in trying to launch an App, it enabled us to avoid many common mistakes. My sense is that App School could do the same.</p>
<p>As I said <a href="http://twitter.com/conoro/status/2128806675">on Twitter earlier</a>, I believe that iPhone &amp; Android development could be to techie teenagers what the ZX Spectrum, C64 and BBC Micro were to my generation. I am what I am today because I got a Speccy when I was 14. I taught myself Basic, Forth and Z80 assembler. I even had games published in magazines. Imagine being 15 years old and having people download your App from the iPhone App Store or Android Market. The buzz!</p>
<p>I want to see the next generation of people coming out of technical course in third level education with at least one mobile app and one webapp in their portfolio. The days when Java skills got you a job in a bank are over.</p>
<p>Well done everyone involved in getting App School launched. Looking forward to seeing what the Alumni develop.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2009/06/irish-iphone-app-school-announced/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
