<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web 2 Ireland &#187; chris shipley</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/chris-shipley/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Innovate!Europe Pure Gold</title>
		<link>/2009/02/innovateeurope-pure-gold/</link>
		<comments>/2009/02/innovateeurope-pure-gold/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 09:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carla thompson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris shipley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guidewire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovateeurope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mike sigal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last Wednesday saw the team from Guidewire host a leg of Innovate!Europe in The Digital Exchange in Dublin. And what a day! Chris Shipley, Mike Sigal and Carla Thompson ran the most impressive start-up workshop I have ever encountered. If you missed it, you really missed out. The format was very simple. There were approx 12 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Wednesday saw the team from <a href="http://www.guidewiregroup.com/site/home.html">Guidewire</a> host a leg of <a href="http://www.innovate-events.com/">Innovate!Europe</a> in The Digital Exchange in Dublin. And what a day! Chris Shipley, Mike Sigal and Carla Thompson ran the most impressive start-up workshop I have ever encountered. If you missed it, you really missed out.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" title="Innovate!Europe" src="//www.innovate-events.com/wordpress/wp-content/themes/elements-of-seo/images/innovate-logo.png" alt="" width="187" height="55" /></p>
<p>The format was very simple. There were approx 12 Irish startups there including <a href="http://www.putplace.com/">PutPlace</a>, <a href="http://www.igopeople.com/">IGOpeople</a>, <a href="http://business.loudervoice.com/">LouderVoice</a>, <a href="http://www.locle.com/">Locle</a>, <a href="http://www.toddle.com/">Toddle</a>. The day kicked off with each of us giving a 90 second elevator pitch. Then we gave our 10 minute company pitch and got feedback from the Guidewire team.</p>
<p>That feedback was accurate, fair, pointed and deeply useful. I gave the first company pitch of the day and everything I heard back from them was spot-on. During the rest of the day I was able to refine the deck quite a bit.</p>
<p>However, it was&#8217;t just the feedback on our own presentation that was valuable, it was hearing about the problems (and successes) in everyone else&#8217;s that made the day so special. As the afternoon progressed, we had more and more discussions involving everyone. This included some excellent insights from Ray Walsh in Enterprise Ireland.</p>
<p>One thing I did notice was the difference between the expectations of  Valley VCs  and Irish ones. I was told I could easily ditch my detailed financials slide in a Valley pitch. I was told the complete opposite as part of the Genesis programme.</p>
<p>The Innovate!Europe roadshow then moved to London on Friday. The remaining venues are:</p>
<ul>
<li>31 MARCH in Bern, Switzerland</li>
<li>3 APRIL in Berlin, Germany</li>
<li>6 APRIL in Paris, France</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are a start-up based on the continent, you owe it to your business to attend one of these sessions. The best companies from the roadshow will then attend a Masterclass in Zaragosa Spain in May. The best of those will take part in a Trade Mission to the Valley in June.</p>
<p>Thanks again to Chris and the team for an invaluable day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2009/02/innovateeurope-pure-gold/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
