<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web 2 Ireland &#187; microsoft ireland</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/microsoft-ireland/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>cmypitch launches in Ireland</title>
		<link>/2009/06/cmypitch-launches-in-ireland/</link>
		<comments>/2009/06/cmypitch-launches-in-ireland/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 13:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cmypitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emmett kilduff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft ireland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.web2ireland.org/?p=1284</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[cmypitch, founded by Irishman, Emmett Kilduff, has just launched in Ireland &#8220;It will connect entrepreneurs with investors. cmypitch.ie provides businesses with the unique opportunity to upload their own video pitch onto the secure platform, for a registered network of investors to watch and inform their investment decisions. In addition, entrepreneurs can learn how to become [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://cmypitch.ie/ie">cmypitch</a>, founded by Irishman, <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/urlurl">Emmett  Kilduff</a>, has just launched in Ireland</p>
<p><em>&#8220;It will connect entrepreneurs with investors. cmypitch.ie provides businesses with the unique opportunity to upload their own video pitch onto the secure platform, for a registered network of investors to watch and inform their investment decisions. In addition, entrepreneurs can learn how to become &#8220;investor ready&#8221; by watching video tips from the best Irish (e.g. Eddie Jordan, Ray Nolan) and international (e.g. Doug Richard, James Caan) entrepreneurs and by downloading the best &#8216;how to&#8217; guides.</p>
<p>For investors, cmypitch.ie has the potential to open up all of Ireland&#8217;s best investment opportunities and makes identifying the most attractive deals more efficient. Investors can save valuable time, allowing them to not only assess the business opportunity but also the people behind the proposition. Pitches can be filtered by size, sector and rating &#8211; all key considerations for investors. Investors can also receive email alerts when a new pitch is added that matches their preferred criteria.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>cmypitch.ie will also hold regular offline pitching events called &#8220;cmypitch Live&#8221;, where entrepreneurs get the unique opportunity to pitch to a room full of investors. Events like these will offer entrepreneurs the opportunity to complement their video pitch with more traditional face-to-face pitching and networking. </p>
<p>cmypitch.ie has been endorsed by some very successful Irish entrepreneurs: Eddie Jordan (F1), Philip Lynch (IAWS, One51), Patrick Brazel (former Chairman of Irish Software Association), James Morris (Windmill Lane, TV3) and Tony Kilduff (Kindle).</p>
<p>cmypitch.ie has already signed several partners: Bank of Scotland (Ireland), Deloitte, The Irish Times, Microsoft and William Fry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2009/06/cmypitch-launches-in-ireland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web2Ireland Logo Competition</title>
		<link>/2008/04/web2ireland-logo-competition/</link>
		<comments>/2008/04/web2ireland-logo-competition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 10:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blacknight solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polldaddy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web2ireland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.web2ireland.org/?p=585</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To complement our lovely new design we thought it might be cool to get a logo to go with it too. This wouldn&#8217;t just be for the site but also for events etc. David Lenehan from PollDaddy came up with the very smart idea on Twitter of running a competition with prizes. Within minutes we [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To complement our lovely new design we thought it might be cool to get a logo to go with it too. This wouldn&#8217;t just be for the site but also for events etc.</p>
<p>David Lenehan from <a href="http://www.polldaddy.com/">PollDaddy</a> came up with the very smart idea on Twitter of running a competition with prizes. Within minutes we had several offers for those prizes. So we&#8217;d like to announce the competition now.</p>
<p>The  rules are simple, just send us a sample of your logo(s) in one of the standard bitmap formats by Friday May 2nd to web2ireland DOT editor AT gmail DOT com. We will then publish a post showing them all and a poll allowing you to vote on them. The design with the most votes after one week wins!</p>
<p>The winner will not just get lots of publicity here and a permanent credit on the site but they will also win the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>One year of PollDaddy Pro sponsored by <a href="http://www.polldaddy.com/">PollDaddy</a></li>
<li>A copy of Microsoft Expression Studio sponsored by <a href="http://www.microsoft.ie/">Microsoft Ireland</a></li>
<li>A year of Blacknight VPS hosting sponsored by <a href="http://www.blacknight.ie/">Blacknight Solutions</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Many thanks to David, Martha, Clare and Michele for the brilliant prizes!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2008/04/web2ireland-logo-competition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
