<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web 2 Ireland &#187; entrepreneurship</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/entrepreneurship/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Enterprise Start in Sligo</title>
		<link>/2008/09/enterprise-start-in-sligo/</link>
		<comments>/2008/09/enterprise-start-in-sligo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 17:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise start]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=713</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve heard nothing but good things about the EnterpriseStart programme in Cork. It was a real lifeline to many Motorola employees last year. The idea is to give basic business skills to those looking to set up their own companies. Mary Boyle let us know that they run the same scheme in Sligo and the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve heard nothing but good things about the <a href="http://www.enterprise-ireland.com/StartBusiness/EnterpriseSTART+Programme.htm">EnterpriseStart</a> programme in Cork. It was a real lifeline to many Motorola employees last year. The idea is to give basic business skills to those looking to set up their own companies.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone" title="Enterprise Start" src="//www.enterprise-ireland.com/NR/rdonlyres/60892AEB-941A-4337-AC42-115B5571031E/0/EIStartbanner.jpg" alt="" width="144" height="79" /></p>
<p>Mary Boyle let us know that they run the same scheme in Sligo and the next one is coming up. If you are even considering making the leap then it&#8217;s worth popping down to hear what it&#8217;s all about.</p>
<blockquote><p>A free information evening will take place in The Glasshouse Hotel, Sligo on 23rd September.  Hear from experts on the supports available to entrepreneurs and from companies who have already set up.  Liam Birkett will be the guest speaker on the night.  Liam's career began in office management in the grocery trade and extended into sales and marketing. He was involved in the launch of Mace and VG group in Ireland. His experience extended into wholesale, retail, cash &amp; carry, and consultancy on a national and international basis before moving to O'Kennedy Brindley Advertising (later to become Saatchi &amp; Saatchi).  With colleagues from the advertising agency, he founded Bernardini, Birkett &amp; Gardner Ltd, a design &amp; marketing consultancy which, for more than 20 years was responsible for corporate identities and many marketing initiatives for Stokes, Kennedy Crowley, Waterford Foods, Monaghan Co-op, Smurfit Group, The K Club, The new GAA branding as well as graphic and packaging projects for a long list of high profile clients.</p>
<p>The evening will kick off at 6pm.  For more information please contact Mary Boyle on 071 9159700 or mary.boyle@enterprise-ireland.com</p>
<p>UPDATE: The programme is happening in Cork too in October.  It is delivered by a mix of trainers and entrepreneurs, over six weekends, and at the end of the programme participants file a short feasibility study. The participant is then given a mentor for 5 sessions. The total cost of the programme is €275, with the balance of costs funded by EI and FAS. Contact Paul DOT Healy AT cit DOT ie for details</p>
<p> </p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2008/09/enterprise-start-in-sligo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
