<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web 2 Ireland &#187; dopplr</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/dopplr/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>MAXroam partners with Dopplr</title>
		<link>/2009/01/maxroam-partners-with-dopplr/</link>
		<comments>/2009/01/maxroam-partners-with-dopplr/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 23:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Irish Web2.0 News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dopplr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maxroam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web2ireland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.web2ireland.org/?p=1004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just picked up from Pat Phelan, founder and CEO of Maxroam&#8217;s blog on the news that MAXroam has partnered with Dopplr Congratulations to Pat and team &#8211; and no doubt this is the first of many white label partnerships we will see from them in 2009 Press Release below&#8230; Cubic Telecom partners with Dopplr to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just picked up from Pat Phelan, founder and CEO of Maxroam&#8217;s blog on the news that <a href="http://patphelan.net/maxroam-partners-with-dopplr/">MAXroam has partnered with Dopplr</a></p>
<p><img src="//farm4.static.flickr.com/3096/3228489705_550881c6d6.jpg?v=0" alt="maxroam on dopplr" /></p>
<p>Congratulations to Pat and team &#8211; and no doubt this is the first of many white label partnerships we will see from them in 2009</p>
<p>Press Release below&#8230;</p>
<p>Cubic Telecom partners with Dopplr to help travelers save thousands on roaming mobile user</p>
<p>MAXroam, the mobile roaming product from Cork-based Cubic Telecom, will be available in Dopplr&#8217;s online travel shop. Dopplr is an online service for smarter travel that helps the world&#8217;s most frequent travelers meet up with their trusted friends and colleagues around the globe. </p>
<p>Today Dopplr announced an online store with MAXroam as one of the key products. The store, which is available to all Dopplr travelers, contains a number of special offers on products and services to make travel better. </p>
<p>Speaking about the partnership, Cubic Telecom&#8217;s CEO Pat Phelan stated &#8220;We&#8217;re delighted to be working with Dopplr. MaxRoam&#8217;s  SIM card will enable Dopplr travelers to save a minimum of 70% on their mobile travel bills.&#8221;</p>
<p>Within nine months of its launch in September 2007, MaxRoam had saved travelers more than $1 million on their roaming mobile bill and almost $1.7 million to date. These savings will now be extended to Dopplr members with a Dopplr SIM and website to manage their mobile usage while traveling.</p>
<p><strong>About Dopplr &#8211; www.dopplr.com</strong></p>
<p>Dopplr is an online service for smarter travel. Dopplr helps you make more of your travels by sharing your future trips privately with friends and colleagues. The service then highlights coincidences, for example, telling you that three people you know will be in Tokyo when you will be there too. You can use Dopplr on your personal computer or mobile phone. It links with many popular online calendars and social networks. </p>
<p><strong>About Cubic Telecom</strong></p>
<p>Cubic Telecom is one of the world&#8217;s first and largest suppliers of travel SIMs, which abolish high roaming fees that are usually charged by incumbent Mobile Network Operators (MNOs).</p>
<p>The company offers a 100% white label platform where MVNOs can customize everything as their own, including having their own branding of SIMs and web portal, plus customized audio prompts and short-codes.</p>
<p>MVNOs can set up multiple sub-distributors, each with their own discrete pricing, and customization, through Cubic&#8217;s innovative new offering.</p>
<div class="cbw snap_nopreview">
<div class="cbw_header"><script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/javascripts/widget.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<div class="cbw_header_text"><a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/">CrunchBase Information</a></div>
</div>
<div class="cbw_content">
<div class="cbw_subheader"><a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/cubictelecom">Cubic Telecom</a></div>
<div class="cbw_subcontent"><script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/cbw/company/cubictelecom.js" type="text/javascript"></script></div>
<div class="cbw_footer">Information provided by <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/">CrunchBase</a></div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2009/01/maxroam-partners-with-dopplr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
