<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
		>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Gateway Ireland</title>
	<atom:link href="/2010/03/gateway-ireland/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 15:37:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Kevin Roache</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1160</link>
		<dc:creator>Kevin Roache</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 09:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1160</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I thing it is a wonderful idea. Good luck with it.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I thing it is a wonderful idea. Good luck with it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Neil Leyden</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1159</link>
		<dc:creator>Neil Leyden</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 09:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1159</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is great to hear the input from everyone on this thread. Gateway Ireland is just looking at resourcing the next phase of development where the emphasis will be on engaging the community (love Kevin Carroll&#039;s post above!!) and getting their input and feedback and helping shape the idea of what Gateway Ireland is and can be. As I said on my own blog post - http://blog.calico.ie/2010/05/launch-of-gateway-ireland-initiative.html - the Seminar was just putting across a vision for what it might be. Something to react against or for. The invite only event wasn&#039;t - I don&#039;t think - meant to be an exclusive thing - it was really just an event - and was aimed at stakeholders who mightn&#039;t be as familiar as the online community with the opportunity web technologies now offer (remember not everyone is as &quot;au fait&quot; with the web as people on the web may think!!!!). Putting the videos online has now given everyone the opportunity to &quot;attend&quot; the event, so to speak-  isn&#039;t that the wonderfully democratizing joy of the internet?!! So hope no-one feels put out - it wasn&#039;t the attention. My role in the project was advising for the preliminary stage - so I&#039;m not a spokesperson or anything. I got involved because I think it is a really worthwhile endeavour coming from a good place and is a real opportunity of the moment.  So I hope that Gateway will be in the position shortly to start engaging for the next phase and getting the obvious positive sentiment that I see on these pages mobilised to good effect. And thanks to Fergus for hosting this thread!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is great to hear the input from everyone on this thread. Gateway Ireland is just looking at resourcing the next phase of development where the emphasis will be on engaging the community (love Kevin Carroll&#8217;s post above!!) and getting their input and feedback and helping shape the idea of what Gateway Ireland is and can be. As I said on my own blog post &#8211; <a href="http://blog.calico.ie/2010/05/launch-of-gateway-ireland-initiative.html" rel="nofollow">http://blog.calico.ie/2010/05/launch-of-gateway-ireland-initiative.html</a> &#8211; the Seminar was just putting across a vision for what it might be. Something to react against or for. The invite only event wasn&#8217;t &#8211; I don&#8217;t think &#8211; meant to be an exclusive thing &#8211; it was really just an event &#8211; and was aimed at stakeholders who mightn&#8217;t be as familiar as the online community with the opportunity web technologies now offer (remember not everyone is as &#8220;au fait&#8221; with the web as people on the web may think!!!!). Putting the videos online has now given everyone the opportunity to &#8220;attend&#8221; the event, so to speak-  isn&#8217;t that the wonderfully democratizing joy of the internet?!! So hope no-one feels put out &#8211; it wasn&#8217;t the attention. My role in the project was advising for the preliminary stage &#8211; so I&#8217;m not a spokesperson or anything. I got involved because I think it is a really worthwhile endeavour coming from a good place and is a real opportunity of the moment.  So I hope that Gateway will be in the position shortly to start engaging for the next phase and getting the obvious positive sentiment that I see on these pages mobilised to good effect. And thanks to Fergus for hosting this thread!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Kevin Carroll</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1158</link>
		<dc:creator>Kevin Carroll</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 06:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The first of Mr. Regan&#039;s two June 13 posts was particularly meaningful to me.  I am in complete agreement with his statement that &quot;...what it means to be of Irish descent in another country would be a good place [for Gateway Ireland] to start. Build from the ground upwards.&quot;

My paternal grandfather was an immigrant from Carrigdangan Townland in County Cork who ultimately settled in rural Minnesota. He died when I was very young, and for that reason and various others I was largely oblivious to my Irish heritage until a cousin took me to a now-defunct pub called McCafferty&#039;s in St. Paul, Minnesota in 1982.  McCafferty&#039;s was, at that time, one of the few places in Minnesota where one could hear live, traditional Irish music on a regular basis.  I was enthralled within seconds of arriving.

Millions of Americans of Irish descent have probably had such &quot;aha&quot; moments -- a pivotal experience that kindled or reawakened their interest in Ireland and its culture. For me, it ultimately led to actions of the type that Gateway Ireland presumably wants to encourage, including the co-founding of two local &quot;trad&quot; bands, years of step-dancing lessons for my three children, trips to Ireland, purchases of Irish products, etc.

That interest in &quot;all things Irish&quot; ultimately prompted me and a number of like-minded volunteers to create the non-profit &quot;Minnesota Irish Cultural Center&quot; in 2009. Our goal is to provide services, facilities and a degree of &quot;centralization&quot; for the dozens of Minnesota clubs and organizations that are currently promoting and celebrating Irish music, dance, language, history, sports, genealogy, travel, commerce, etc.  In effect, we hope and intend to become the primary &quot;gateway to Ireland&quot; for the 600,000 Minnesotans who claimed Irish ancestry in the 2000 census (and for any other Minnesotans who are interested in Ireland, for that matter).

Gates swing both ways.  Organizations (like ours) with an Irish focus are natural portals for Gateway Ireland&#039;s outreach activities. In one of the on-line videos that I&#039;ve seen, Mr. Leyden talks about &quot;identifying the diaspora and connecting with them.&quot;  Well, here we are, and we&#039;re ready and willing to make new and mutually beneficial connections of the type envisioned by Gateway Ireland.

Mr. Leyden and others have also discussed the possibility of establishing &quot;electronic embassies&quot; around the globe to help carry out Gateway Ireland&#039;s goals.  The Minnesota Irish Cultural Center would be proud to be part of such an endeavor.  Anyone who is interested in discussing or exploring that possibility is invited to contact me at k.carroll@MnIrish.org. Thanks, and good luck to those who are devoting their time and energy to this exciting new initiative!

Kevin Carroll, Executive Director, Minnesota Irish Cultural Center (www.MnIrish.org)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first of Mr. Regan&#8217;s two June 13 posts was particularly meaningful to me.  I am in complete agreement with his statement that &#8220;&#8230;what it means to be of Irish descent in another country would be a good place [for Gateway Ireland] to start. Build from the ground upwards.&#8221;</p>
<p>My paternal grandfather was an immigrant from Carrigdangan Townland in County Cork who ultimately settled in rural Minnesota. He died when I was very young, and for that reason and various others I was largely oblivious to my Irish heritage until a cousin took me to a now-defunct pub called McCafferty&#8217;s in St. Paul, Minnesota in 1982.  McCafferty&#8217;s was, at that time, one of the few places in Minnesota where one could hear live, traditional Irish music on a regular basis.  I was enthralled within seconds of arriving.</p>
<p>Millions of Americans of Irish descent have probably had such &#8220;aha&#8221; moments &#8212; a pivotal experience that kindled or reawakened their interest in Ireland and its culture. For me, it ultimately led to actions of the type that Gateway Ireland presumably wants to encourage, including the co-founding of two local &#8220;trad&#8221; bands, years of step-dancing lessons for my three children, trips to Ireland, purchases of Irish products, etc.</p>
<p>That interest in &#8220;all things Irish&#8221; ultimately prompted me and a number of like-minded volunteers to create the non-profit &#8220;Minnesota Irish Cultural Center&#8221; in 2009. Our goal is to provide services, facilities and a degree of &#8220;centralization&#8221; for the dozens of Minnesota clubs and organizations that are currently promoting and celebrating Irish music, dance, language, history, sports, genealogy, travel, commerce, etc.  In effect, we hope and intend to become the primary &#8220;gateway to Ireland&#8221; for the 600,000 Minnesotans who claimed Irish ancestry in the 2000 census (and for any other Minnesotans who are interested in Ireland, for that matter).</p>
<p>Gates swing both ways.  Organizations (like ours) with an Irish focus are natural portals for Gateway Ireland&#8217;s outreach activities. In one of the on-line videos that I&#8217;ve seen, Mr. Leyden talks about &#8220;identifying the diaspora and connecting with them.&#8221;  Well, here we are, and we&#8217;re ready and willing to make new and mutually beneficial connections of the type envisioned by Gateway Ireland.</p>
<p>Mr. Leyden and others have also discussed the possibility of establishing &#8220;electronic embassies&#8221; around the globe to help carry out Gateway Ireland&#8217;s goals.  The Minnesota Irish Cultural Center would be proud to be part of such an endeavor.  Anyone who is interested in discussing or exploring that possibility is invited to contact me at <a href="mailto:k.carroll@MnIrish.org">k.carroll@MnIrish.org</a>. Thanks, and good luck to those who are devoting their time and energy to this exciting new initiative!</p>
<p>Kevin Carroll, Executive Director, Minnesota Irish Cultural Center (www.MnIrish.org)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mick Regan</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1157</link>
		<dc:creator>Mick Regan</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 14:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1157</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Al,

Yep a complex issue. A mixture of social history, culture, and political influence over time that seemed to create a divide (a cutting of the cord) whenever someone emigrated. Probably because Ireland was historically quite inward looking and parochial in its make up.

Two things have happened - globalisation and a recession. The former creates a natural path where Ireland may see a mutual advantage in re-engaging with its diaspora, the latter runs the risk of ensuing actions being perceived as exploititive.

It&#039;s the latter area that concerns me, and hence the view that a change in the relationship needs to stem from the ground up. A shift in the mindset of the ordinary guy in the street.

If this is to be achieved it also needs momentum at state level. A clear purposeful long term strategy that goes beyond sound bites - not one that makes a government look like it&#039;s doing something, but one that IS actually doing something.

The current trend seems to be to take an idea and throw it out to the private sector to see if they&#039;ll run with it. Whilst that does at least create activity I think the Irish and Irish descent abroad would also like to see state driven initiatives.

In essence a message from the country of Ireland that it wants an equal relationship, that it understands the value of heritage for those who live abroad, and that it is prepared to accept ideas and put value on the experiences and skills of those who return or emigrate back.

When you&#039;ve got a government whose back is to the wall there&#039;s a risk of short-sightedness and ill thought out ideas. Or worse, good ideas getting badly implemented.

Gateway-Ireland looks like a positive (privately driven) initiative and should have benefits at a commercial level. Hopefully the words of Gabriel Byrne will also resonate and form part of the character of whatever the end result turns out to be.

I guess what i&#039;m trying to say is that &#039;diaspora projects&#039; should have a meaningful and honest nature and that they need to have substance at a personal / individual level, and once that&#039;s in place economic benefits will follow and evolve quite naturally anyway. 

Focus on the relationship first, get it right - &#039;build it and they will come&#039;.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Al,</p>
<p>Yep a complex issue. A mixture of social history, culture, and political influence over time that seemed to create a divide (a cutting of the cord) whenever someone emigrated. Probably because Ireland was historically quite inward looking and parochial in its make up.</p>
<p>Two things have happened &#8211; globalisation and a recession. The former creates a natural path where Ireland may see a mutual advantage in re-engaging with its diaspora, the latter runs the risk of ensuing actions being perceived as exploititive.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the latter area that concerns me, and hence the view that a change in the relationship needs to stem from the ground up. A shift in the mindset of the ordinary guy in the street.</p>
<p>If this is to be achieved it also needs momentum at state level. A clear purposeful long term strategy that goes beyond sound bites &#8211; not one that makes a government look like it&#8217;s doing something, but one that IS actually doing something.</p>
<p>The current trend seems to be to take an idea and throw it out to the private sector to see if they&#8217;ll run with it. Whilst that does at least create activity I think the Irish and Irish descent abroad would also like to see state driven initiatives.</p>
<p>In essence a message from the country of Ireland that it wants an equal relationship, that it understands the value of heritage for those who live abroad, and that it is prepared to accept ideas and put value on the experiences and skills of those who return or emigrate back.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;ve got a government whose back is to the wall there&#8217;s a risk of short-sightedness and ill thought out ideas. Or worse, good ideas getting badly implemented.</p>
<p>Gateway-Ireland looks like a positive (privately driven) initiative and should have benefits at a commercial level. Hopefully the words of Gabriel Byrne will also resonate and form part of the character of whatever the end result turns out to be.</p>
<p>I guess what i&#8217;m trying to say is that &#8216;diaspora projects&#8217; should have a meaningful and honest nature and that they need to have substance at a personal / individual level, and once that&#8217;s in place economic benefits will follow and evolve quite naturally anyway. </p>
<p>Focus on the relationship first, get it right &#8211; &#8216;build it and they will come&#8217;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Al Wayson</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1156</link>
		<dc:creator>Al Wayson</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 11:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1156</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These diaspora projects usually assume we need to make an effort to catch the eye of our diaspora, that it&#039;s a prodigal son kind of relationship. There also seems to be an assumption that our diaspora is doing so well abroad that the best we can do is to pick their brains occasionally or get a few more Euro off them when they come back on holidays.

My situation is different. I was a member of the Irish diaspora throughout the 90&#039;s, working in emerging technology at a senior level with a high-profile international organisation. I came back to Ireland in 2000 expecting to be able to make a contribution here and assuming I would slot in at a similar level. After all this was Celtic Tiger Ireland but boy was I wrong. 

Nobody here showed the slightest interest in the experience I had gained abroad. So I knuckled down and found my own work. For the record, during the last ten years, I have been employed for one year, unemployed for two years and self-employed for seven years. 

By comparison, a friend of mine from Finland, who came to Ireland to study and get some work experience was welcomed with open arms when she returned to her home country with an international qualification, immediately getting a job with a state agency and has just returned from the Expo in Shanghai.

I believe this happened because relatively few people leave Finland and the experience of returning immigrants is valued whereas millions have emigrated from Ireland over the years. Perhaps we have become immune to emigration, hence most returning immigrants are feted by nobody other than their families.

So maybe one of our schemes should be to enagage the diaspora by treating their achievements with more respect and placing more value on their experience. Then maybe more of them would return and make a contribution to the economy here. Meanwhile I am trying to make my own contribution, but as far as I am concerned, I am not the prodigal son, Ireland is the prodigal country]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These diaspora projects usually assume we need to make an effort to catch the eye of our diaspora, that it&#8217;s a prodigal son kind of relationship. There also seems to be an assumption that our diaspora is doing so well abroad that the best we can do is to pick their brains occasionally or get a few more Euro off them when they come back on holidays.</p>
<p>My situation is different. I was a member of the Irish diaspora throughout the 90&#8242;s, working in emerging technology at a senior level with a high-profile international organisation. I came back to Ireland in 2000 expecting to be able to make a contribution here and assuming I would slot in at a similar level. After all this was Celtic Tiger Ireland but boy was I wrong. </p>
<p>Nobody here showed the slightest interest in the experience I had gained abroad. So I knuckled down and found my own work. For the record, during the last ten years, I have been employed for one year, unemployed for two years and self-employed for seven years. </p>
<p>By comparison, a friend of mine from Finland, who came to Ireland to study and get some work experience was welcomed with open arms when she returned to her home country with an international qualification, immediately getting a job with a state agency and has just returned from the Expo in Shanghai.</p>
<p>I believe this happened because relatively few people leave Finland and the experience of returning immigrants is valued whereas millions have emigrated from Ireland over the years. Perhaps we have become immune to emigration, hence most returning immigrants are feted by nobody other than their families.</p>
<p>So maybe one of our schemes should be to enagage the diaspora by treating their achievements with more respect and placing more value on their experience. Then maybe more of them would return and make a contribution to the economy here. Meanwhile I am trying to make my own contribution, but as far as I am concerned, I am not the prodigal son, Ireland is the prodigal country</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Mick Regan</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1155</link>
		<dc:creator>Mick Regan</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 01:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1155</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Having setup diaspora.ie as a hobby (and as a learning exercise - 1st website), one thing i&#039;ve learned is that until Ireland reestablishes an equal two-way relationship with its diaspora that relationship will remain somewhat disjointed.

Gabriel Byrne has his finger on the pulse (http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/ireland/2010/0527/1224271230301.html), and i think his motivation is genuine, but there are a few questionable indicators from the state.

An example would be the proposal for a diaspora discount card (http://www.breakingnews.ie/ireland/discount-card-plan-for-tourists-with-irish-roots-458240.html). The idea itself I think is good (submitted the same myself to yourcountryyourcall in March), but the suggestion that it should be limited to 5 years sends the wrong message.

To make this work better the drive needs to come from all levels of society. Some moves from the government and our national broadcaster reminding us about the history of the diaspora, and what it means to be of Irish descent in another country would be a good place to start. Build from the ground upwards.

We&#039;ll know we&#039;re getting it right when an Irish-American walks down an Irish street and genuinely gets the feel that we&#039;re welcoming him home.

Anyway just the gist of my thoughts, but hopefully striking a cord somewhere.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having setup diaspora.ie as a hobby (and as a learning exercise &#8211; 1st website), one thing i&#8217;ve learned is that until Ireland reestablishes an equal two-way relationship with its diaspora that relationship will remain somewhat disjointed.</p>
<p>Gabriel Byrne has his finger on the pulse (<a href="http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/ireland/2010/0527/1224271230301.html" rel="nofollow">http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/ireland/2010/0527/1224271230301.html</a>), and i think his motivation is genuine, but there are a few questionable indicators from the state.</p>
<p>An example would be the proposal for a diaspora discount card (<a href="http://www.breakingnews.ie/ireland/discount-card-plan-for-tourists-with-irish-roots-458240.html" rel="nofollow">http://www.breakingnews.ie/ireland/discount-card-plan-for-tourists-with-irish-roots-458240.html</a>). The idea itself I think is good (submitted the same myself to yourcountryyourcall in March), but the suggestion that it should be limited to 5 years sends the wrong message.</p>
<p>To make this work better the drive needs to come from all levels of society. Some moves from the government and our national broadcaster reminding us about the history of the diaspora, and what it means to be of Irish descent in another country would be a good place to start. Build from the ground upwards.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll know we&#8217;re getting it right when an Irish-American walks down an Irish street and genuinely gets the feel that we&#8217;re welcoming him home.</p>
<p>Anyway just the gist of my thoughts, but hopefully striking a cord somewhere.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: James O'Brien</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1154</link>
		<dc:creator>James O'Brien</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 10:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1154</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[irishcentral.com has been doing the Diaspora business for over a year now with major success. It seems common sense that a Diaspora site should be based in that diaspora --it is connected to Irish Voice newspaper and Irish America magazine in New York with 500,000 uniques a month.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>irishcentral.com has been doing the Diaspora business for over a year now with major success. It seems common sense that a Diaspora site should be based in that diaspora &#8211;it is connected to Irish Voice newspaper and Irish America magazine in New York with 500,000 uniques a month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Al Wayson</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1153</link>
		<dc:creator>Al Wayson</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 23:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1153</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I welcome the news of Gateway Ireland and enjoyed watching the videos of the Dublin Castle event. However I have two concerns. These are not specific Gateway Ireland, but it does bring them to mind. 

First off, Farmleigh was an invitation only-event and now &quot;son-of-Farmleigh&quot; Gateway Ireland holds its own invitation-only event. Its ironic that economic salvation based on community building and open source technologies are enshrined in initiatives that are being discussed and developed behind closed doors. 

Seondly, how was the Gateway Ireland team put together? I&#039;m guessing it was through personal contact and referral. So is really the best core team for the job? Time will tell. As far as I know the project manager Neil Leyden is also managing the International Content Services Centre project and if so is in danger of becoming the Laura Magahy of the 21st Century! 

My overall concern is that the 20th century business inscestuousness and masonic practices that got us into the mess we are currently in will continue unbridled into the future. This means that despite the wonderful technologies we have at our disposal, over-engineering, poor execution and sometimes sheer incompetence will continue to prevail. 

Sorry to use Gateway Ireland as a sacrificial cow for my comments, I think its objectives are great and I don&#039;t doubt its sincerity. However its list of advisors http://www.gateway-ireland.com/index.php?page=advisors contains many names which are on similar lists for many other initiatives. Which again sets off alarm bells. The composition of these advisory lists almost seems lazy at this stage.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I welcome the news of Gateway Ireland and enjoyed watching the videos of the Dublin Castle event. However I have two concerns. These are not specific Gateway Ireland, but it does bring them to mind. </p>
<p>First off, Farmleigh was an invitation only-event and now &#8220;son-of-Farmleigh&#8221; Gateway Ireland holds its own invitation-only event. Its ironic that economic salvation based on community building and open source technologies are enshrined in initiatives that are being discussed and developed behind closed doors. </p>
<p>Seondly, how was the Gateway Ireland team put together? I&#8217;m guessing it was through personal contact and referral. So is really the best core team for the job? Time will tell. As far as I know the project manager Neil Leyden is also managing the International Content Services Centre project and if so is in danger of becoming the Laura Magahy of the 21st Century! </p>
<p>My overall concern is that the 20th century business inscestuousness and masonic practices that got us into the mess we are currently in will continue unbridled into the future. This means that despite the wonderful technologies we have at our disposal, over-engineering, poor execution and sometimes sheer incompetence will continue to prevail. </p>
<p>Sorry to use Gateway Ireland as a sacrificial cow for my comments, I think its objectives are great and I don&#8217;t doubt its sincerity. However its list of advisors <a href="http://www.gateway-ireland.com/index.php?page=advisors" rel="nofollow">http://www.gateway-ireland.com/index.php?page=advisors</a> contains many names which are on similar lists for many other initiatives. Which again sets off alarm bells. The composition of these advisory lists almost seems lazy at this stage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Byrneholics.com &#124; Gabriel Byrne &#187; Connecting the Dots with Gabriel Byrne</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1152</link>
		<dc:creator>Byrneholics.com &#124; Gabriel Byrne &#187; Connecting the Dots with Gabriel Byrne</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 21:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1152</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[...] Discussion about the project at Web2Ireland, with a technologically savvy [...]]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[...] Discussion about the project at Web2Ireland, with a technologically savvy [...]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: John Breslin</title>
		<link>/2010/03/gateway-ireland/#comment-1151</link>
		<dc:creator>John Breslin</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 01:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://web2ireland.org/?p=1674#comment-1151</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi John -

Yeah I guess I&#039;d be more interested in hearing what the purpose of using Semantic Web stuff is - Semantic Web is a means to an end, e.g. bringing together distributed contributions from the Irish diaspora into this portal, or getting the content that&#039;s on there more accessible to search engines or for pumping into Facebook using the Open Graph Protocol.

The purpose of this needs to be thought out - if it&#039;s to get industry to set up here, then maybe the portal isn&#039;t needed - you just need to fly them over here and show them what we&#039;ve got - but if it&#039;s to help Irish people to network and leverage opportunities, maybe there&#039;s something in it.

John.
--]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi John -</p>
<p>Yeah I guess I&#8217;d be more interested in hearing what the purpose of using Semantic Web stuff is &#8211; Semantic Web is a means to an end, e.g. bringing together distributed contributions from the Irish diaspora into this portal, or getting the content that&#8217;s on there more accessible to search engines or for pumping into Facebook using the Open Graph Protocol.</p>
<p>The purpose of this needs to be thought out &#8211; if it&#8217;s to get industry to set up here, then maybe the portal isn&#8217;t needed &#8211; you just need to fly them over here and show them what we&#8217;ve got &#8211; but if it&#8217;s to help Irish people to network and leverage opportunities, maybe there&#8217;s something in it.</p>
<p>John.<br />
&#8211;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
